<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Pokemon Deck</string>
    <string name="bulbasaur_text">Bulbasaur is a small, quadruped Pokemon that has blue-green skin
        with darker green patches. It has red eyes with white pupils and pointed, ear-like
        structures on top of its head. Its snout is short and blunt, and it has a wide mouth.
        A pair of small, pointed teeth are visible in the upper jaw when its mouth is open. Each of
        its thick legs ends with three sharp claws. On its back is a green plant bulb, which is
        grown from a seed planted there at birth. The bulb provides it with energy through
        photosynthesis as well as from the nutrient-rich seeds contained within. As mentioned in
        the anime, starter Pokemon are raised by Breeders to be distributed to new Trainers. Having
        been domesticated from birth, Bulbasaur is regarded as both a rare and well-behaved
        Pokemon. It is known to be extremely loyal, even after long-term abandonment. Bulbasaur has
        also shown itself to be an excellent caretaker, even having a special technique called the
        \&quot;Bulba-by\&quot;. To perform this technique, Bulbasaur uses its vines to pick up a young Pokemon
        and soothingly rocks it in the air. It is found in grasslands and forests throughout the
        Kanto region. However, due to Bulbasaur\&apos;s status as starter Pokemon, it is hard to come by
        in the wild and generally found under the ownership of a Trainer. It has been observed that
        a Bulbasaur\&apos;s bulb will flash blue when it is ready to evolve. If it does not want to
        evolve, it struggles to resist the transformation. Many Bulbasaur gather every year in a
        hidden garden in Kanto to evolve into Ivysaur in a ceremony led by a Venusaur.</string>
    <string name="ivysaur_text">Ivysaur is a quadruped Pokemon similar to a dinosaur. It has
        blue-green skin with darker patches. On top of its head are pointed ears with black inside, 
        and it has narrow red eyes. It has a short, rounded snout with a wide mouth. Two pointed 
        teeth protrude from its upper jaw. Each of its feet have three claws on them. The bulb on 
        its back has bloomed into a large pink bud. A short brown trunk surrounded by leafy green 
        fronds supports the bud. The weight of the plant prevents Ivysaur from standing on its hind 
        legs and forces its legs to grow sturdy. When its flower is ready to bloom, it gives off a 
        distinct, strong sweet-smelling aroma and starts swelling. Ivysaur will also start spending 
        more time in sunlight in preparation for its upcoming evolution. Exposure to sunlight adds 
        to the strength of both Ivysaur and its plant. Ivysaur\&apos;s natural habitat is plains.
        However, it is rare, as many are in captivity.</string>
    <string name="venusaur_text">Venusaur is a squat, quadruped Pokemon with bumpy, blue-green skin.
        It has small, circular red eyes, a short, blunt snout, and a wide mouth with two pointed
        teeth in the upper jaw and four in the lower jaw. On top of its head are small, pointed ears
        with reddish pink insides. It has three clawed toes on each foot. The bud on its back has
        bloomed in a large pink, white-spotted flower. The flower is supported by a thick, brown
        trunk surrounded by green fronds. A female Venusaur will have a seed in the center of its
        flower. As Mega Venusaur, the flower on its back grows larger and two smaller pink flowers
        bloom, one on its forehead and one on its rear. The weight of the flower causes its legs to
        become sturdier in order to support it.[1] Additional leaves with woody stems, which are
        supported by vines, are grown around the flower. Mega Venusaur also develops dark markings
        on its forehead below the new flower. Venusaur uses its flower to catch the sun\&apos;s rays to
        convert them into energy, which causes the flower to take on colors that are more vibrant.
        The flower releases a soothing scent that attracts Pokemon. This scent becomes stronger
        after a rainy day. In the anime, Venusaur has demonstrated the ability to manipulate nature
        and lead evolution ceremonies for Bulbasaur and Ivysaur. This Pokemon is rarely found in the
        wild, but has been known to inhabit grasslands.</string>
    <string name="charmander_text">Charmander is a bipedal, reptilian Pokemon with a primarily
        orange body. Its underside from the chest down and soles are cream-colored. It has two small
        fangs visible in its upper jaw and two smaller fangs in its lower jaw. Charmander has blue
        eyes. Its arms and legs are short with four fingers and three clawed toes. A fire burns at
        the tip of this Pokemon\&apos;s slender tail, and has blazed there since Charmander\&apos;s birth. The
        flame can be used as an indication of Charmander\&apos;s health and mood, burning brightly when
        the Pokemon is strong, weakly when it is exhausted, wavering when it is happy, and blazing
        when it is enraged. It is said that Charmander dies if its flame goes out. However, if the
        Pokemon is healthy, the flame will continue to burn if gets a bit wet and is said to steam
        in the rain. Charmander can be found in hot, mountainous areas. However, it is found far
        more often in the ownership of Trainers. As shown in Pokemon Snap, Charmander exhibits pack
        behavior, calling others of its species if it finds food.</string>
    <string name="charmeleon_text">Charmeleon is a bipedal, reptilian creature. It has crimson 
        scales and a cream underside. There is a horn-like protrusion on the back of its head, and 
        it has narrow green eyes and a long snout. It has relatively long arms with three sharp 
        claws. Its short legs have feet with three claws and cream-colored soles. The tip of its 
        long, powerful tail has a flame burning on it. The temperature rises to unbearable levels 
        if Charmeleon swings its tail. Charmeleon has a vicious nature and will constantly seek out 
        opponents. Strong opponents excite this Pokemon, causing it to spout bluish-white flames
        that torch its surroundings. However, it will relax once it has won. It is rare in the 
        wild, but it can be found in mountainous areas.</string>
    <string name="charizard_text">Charmeleon is a bipedal, reptilian creature. It has crimson scales
        and a cream underside. There is a horn-like protrusion on the back of its head, and it has
        narrow green eyes and a long snout. It has relatively long arms with three sharp claws. Its
        short legs have feet with three claws and cream-colored soles. The tip of its long, powerful
        tail has a flame burning on it. The temperature rises to unbearable levels if Charmeleon
        swings its tail. Charmeleon has a vicious nature and will constantly seek out opponents.
        Strong opponents excite this Pokemon, causing it to spout bluish-white flames that torch its
        surroundings. However, it will relax once it has won. It is rare in the wild, but it can be
        found in mountainous areas.</string>
    <string name="squirtle_text">Squirtle is a small Pokemon that resembles a light blue turtle.
        While it typically walks on its two short legs, it has been shown to run on all fours in
        Super Smash Bros. Brawl. It has large brown eyes and a slightly hooked upper lip. Each of
        its hands and feet have three pointed digits. The end of its long tail curls inward. Its
        body is encased by a tough shell that forms and hardens after birth. This shell is brown on
        the top, pale yellow on the bottom, and has a thick white ridge between the two halves.
        Squirtle\&apos;s shell is a useful tool. It can withdraw into the shell for protection or for
        sleeping, and its grooved, rounded shape helps to reduce water resistance when this Pokemon
        swims. Squirtle can spray foamy water from its mouth with great accuracy. Squirtle is scarce
        in the wild, although it can be found around small ponds and lakes. The anime has shown that 
        it can be found living on secluded islands with other members of its evolutionary line.
    </string>
    <string name="wartortle_text">Wartortle is a bipedal, indigo-blue Pokemon similar to a turtle.
        It has brown eyes, a dark blue streak on each cheek, and two sharp teeth protruding from its
        upper jaw. It has three clawed fingers and pointed toes. Bluish white fur covers its long
        ears and tail. A brown shell with a pale yellow underside encases its body. A thick, white
        rim separates the upper and lower halves of the shell. As Wartortle grows old, its tail fur
        will darken, and it may have algae growing on its shell. The shell may also carry scars from
        past battles. To maintain balance while swimming at high speeds, Wartortle moves its furry
        ears and tail. It can use the fur to store air for extended underwater diving. Its tail is a
        popular symbol of longevity, making it popular with the elderly. It hides in water when
        hunting and emerges to surprise its prey. The anime has shown that Wartortle can be found
        living in colonies on islands, but its preferred habitat seems to be freshwater ponds and
        lakes.
    </string>
    <string name="blastoise_text">Blastoise is a large, bipedal tortoise-like Pokemon. Its body is
        dark blue and is mostly hidden by its tough, brown shell. This shell has a pale yellow
        underside and a white ridge encircling its arms and separating the upper and lower halves.
        Two powerful water cannons reside in the top sides of its shell. These cannons can be
        extended or withdrawn and can be used to assist in high-speed charges. Blastoise\&apos;s head has
        triangular ears that are black on the inside, small brown eyes, and a cream-colored lower
        jaw. Its arms are thick and striated with three claws on each hand. Its feet have three
        claws on the front and one on the back. It has a stubby tail. As Mega Blastoise, it develops
        two smaller shells over its arms, each with their own water cannon. The two cannons on its
        back are replaced by a single, central water cannon of greater size. This cannon extends
        forward over Mega Blastoise\&apos;s head and is said to have a blast range of over 6 miles. Small
        ridges develop over its, now red, eyes and extend to its ears. The ears angle slightly
        backward and there is a small point on its chin. The powerful cannons on this Pokemon\&apos;s back
        are capable of producing water blasts that can pierce steel and concrete. Blastoise
        deliberately makes itself heavy to withstand these powerful blasts, and it will crush its
        opponents with its bulk. The anime has shown that Blastoise can take the role of a leader in
        large groups of Squirtle and Wartortle. Its preferred habitat seems to be freshwater ponds
        and lakes.
    </string>

    <string-array name="pokemon_description">
        <item>@string/bulbasaur_text</item>
        <item>@string/ivysaur_text</item>
        <item>@string/venusaur_text</item>
        <item>@string/charmander_text</item>
        <item>@string/charmeleon_text</item>
        <item>@string/charizard_text</item>
        <item>@string/squirtle_text</item>
        <item>@string/wartortle_text</item>
        <item>@string/blastoise_text</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
